大家好
Hi, guys!
嘿  菲比  嗨
Hey, Pheebs! Hi!
嘿  对了  约会怎么样
Hey. Oh, oh, how'd it go?
不是很好  他送我到地铁然后说
Um, not so good. He walked me to the subway and said
"我们应该再来一次"
'We should do this again!'
怎么啦  他说要再来一次那不是很好吗
What? He said 'we should do it again', that's good, right?
不  他说我们应该再来一次
Uh, no. Loosely translated 'We should do this again'
代表你将无法再见到裸体的我
means 'You will never see me naked'.
什么时候这样子的
Since when?
一直都是这样  这是约会用语
Since always. It's like dating language.
就像"不是你的问题"代表"就是你"
Y'know, like 'It's not you' means 'It is you'.
"你真的挺好的"代表
Or 'You're such a nice guy' means
"我要和穿皮衣的酒鬼约会"
'I'm gonna be dating leather-wearing alcoholics
然后再跟你抱怨他们"
and complaining about them to you
还有还有  "我们该试试别人"代表
Or, or, y'know, um, 'I think we should see other people' means
"哈哈  我已和别人约会了"
'Ha, ha, I already am'.
-大家都懂  -对  放轻松啦
- And everybody knows this? - Yeah. Cushions the blow.
没错就像你小时候
Yeah, it's like when you're a kid,
父母把你的狗狗送去安乐死
and your parents put your dog to sleep,
却对你说它跑到别人家农场去住了
and they tell you it went off to live on some farm.
真有意思  不是  我是说
That's funny, that, no, because,
我爸妈是真的把我家的狗
uh, our parents actually did, uh,
送别人农场去养了
send our dog off to live on a farm.
罗斯
Uh, Ross.
米尔纳家在康乃迪克州的农场
What? Wh- hello? The Millners' farm in Connecticut?
米尔纳家
The Millners,
他们家的农场好棒
they had this unbelievable farm,
有马还有可供追逐的兔子
and horses, and rabbits that he could chase and it was- it w- .....
哦  我的天  芝芝
Oh, my God, Chi Chi!
"知道自己不久于人世有何感受"
"So how does it feel knowing you're about to die?"
"华顿  我的痛苦将在五分钟内消失
"Warden, in five minutes my pain will be over.
而你  要知道
But you'll have to live with the knowledge that
你让一位诚实的人丢掉了性命
you sent an honest man to die."
嘿  表演得真好
Hey, that was really good!
是吗  谢了  咱们继续吧
Yeah? Thanks! Let's keep going.
好  你要我怎么做呢  达蒙
Okay. "So. Whaddya want from me, Damone, huh?"
我只想回到我的牢房内
"I just wanna go back to my cell.
因为在那里  我可以抽烟
'Cause in my cell, I can smoke."
抽去吧
"Smoke away."
我想这就是达蒙独自在牢房抽烟的原因
I think this is probably why Damone smokes in his cell alone.
-什么  -手放轻松  手腕自然点
- What? - Relax your hand! Let your wrist go.
别太过火
Not so much!
好  吸一口
Alright, now try taking a puff.
很好
Okay.
算了  不对  把烟给我
Okay. No. Give it to me.
你休想  我不会给你烟的
No no no, I am not giving you a cigarette.
没关系啦
It's fine, it's fine.
你到底想不想演这个角色  拿来
Look, do you wanna get this part, or not? Here.
很好  现在
All right, now.
别把它当成是支烟
Don't think of it as a cigarette.
把它当成是你思念已久的东西
Think of it as the thing that's been missing from your hand.
当你夹着它时  感到自在  感到满足
When you're holding it, you feel right. You feel complete.
-你很想它吗  -没  不怎么想
- Y'miss it? - Nah, not so much.
好  现在抽一口
Alright, now we smoke.
哦  爽死了
Oh..my..God.
不对不对  他们说
No, no, no. They say it's the same as the distance
跟从拇指尖到食指尖的距离相等
from the tip of a guy's thumb to the tip of his index finger.
这太荒谬了
That's ridiculous!
我可以用另一个拇指么
Can I use.. either thumb?
好吧  别告诉我  别告诉我
Alright, don't tell me, don't tell me!
无咖啡因卡布其诺是乔伊的
Decaf cappucino for Joey..
黑咖啡
Coffee black..
拿铁
Late..
和冰茶
and an iced tea.
-我进步神速  -是啊  真厉害
- I'm getting pretty good at this! - Yeah. Yeah, excellent.
我真行
Good for me!
菲比  你没事吧
Y'okay, Phoebe?
嗯  不  只是  没啥
Yeah no- I'm just- it's, it's not even worth...
是我存钱的银行
It's my bank.
他们对你怎么了
What did they do to you?
也没怎么  只是  好吧
It's nothing, it's just- Okay.
我当时正在看信  一打开他们的每月
I'm going through my mail, and I open up their monthly,
所谓的  "通知"
you know, STATEMENT-
别激动  别激动
Easy, easy...
发现我户头里多了五百元
and there's five hundred extra dollars in my account.
撤旦的爪牙又来祸害人间啦
Oh, Satan's minions at work again...
没错  因为我得到银行找他们解决处理
Yes, 'cause now I have to go down there, and deal with them.
你脑子中风了吗  自己留着呗
What are you talking about? Keep it!
这钱不是我的  不是我赚来的
It's not mine, I didn't earn it,
我留着  就如同偷窃
if I kept it, it would be like stealing.
对  可如果你把它花了  就如同购物
Yeah, but if you spent it, it would be like shopping!
好吧  就比方说我买了一双很棒的鞋
Okay. Okay, let's say I bought a really great pair of shoes.
你们知道我每踏出一步都会听到什么吗
Do you know what I'd hear, with every step I took?
不是我的
'Not-mine. Not-mine. Not-mine.'
即使我再快乐再雀跃都会听到
And even if I was happy, okay, and, and skipping-I'd hear
不是我的  不是我的  不是我的
'Not-not-mine, not-not-mine, not-not-mine, not-not-mine'...
我们知道你的意思了
We're with you. We got it.
很好  我只是  没办法享受这些钱
Okay. I'd- just- I'd never be able to enjoy it.
因为这就像是沉重的因果报应一样
It would be like this giant karmic debt.
钱德勒  你在干什么
Chandler, what're you doing?
嘿  你在干什么
hey,what are you doing?
哦  我的天
Oh! Oh, God!
这是什么
What is this?!
我在抽烟  我在抽烟  在抽烟
I'm smoking. I'm smoking, I'm smoking.
我真不敢相信你
Oh, I can't believe you!
你一直以来都表现良好  都三年了
You've been so good, for three years!
这是我的奖励
And this- is my reward!
等一下
Hold on a second, alright?
想想你戒烟后是怎么活过来的
Just think about what you went through the last time you quit.
所以这一次我不再戒了
Okay, so this time I won't quit!
熄掉
Ohhh! Put it out!
好吧  我熄掉就是  熄掉了
All right! I'm putting it out, I'm putting it out.
不是吧  现在我没法喝
Oh, no! I- I can't drink this now!
好了  我去换衣服了  有约会
Alright. I'm gonna go change, I've got a date.
又是艾伦  进展如何
So is it Alan again? How's it goin'?
进展得还不错
'S'going pretty good, y'know?
感觉很好  我们在一起很开心
It's nice, and, we're having fun.
我们何时能见到他
So when do we get to meet the guy?
对啊
Yeah!
我看看  今天是星期一
Let's see, today's Monday...
永远别想
Never.
拜托  别这样啦
Oh, come on! Come on!-
不  史蒂夫那次之后就别想了
No. Not after what happened with Steve.
你在说什么  我们都爱史蒂胡
What are you talking about? We love Schhteve!
史蒂胡很性感
Schhteve was schhexy!..
不好意思
Sorry.
我自己都还没清楚对他的感觉呢
Look, I don't even know how I feel about him yet.
给我一点时间想清楚
Just give me a chance to figure that out.
那么  到时我们就可以见他了吗
Well, then can we meet him?
凭什么我得让他们见他啊
I mean, why should I let them meet him?
我带个人回家
I mean, I bring a guy home,
五分钟之内他们便会蜂拥而上
and within five minutes they're all over him.
他们就像丛林狼一样
I mean, they're like- coyotes,
专挑兽群中的弱者下手
picking off the weak members of the herd.
我说  身为一位阅尽天下极品男的人
Listen. As someone who's seen more than her fair share of bad beef,
我告诉你  这事没什么大不了的
I'll tell you: that is not such a terrible thing.
再说了  他们毕竟是你的朋友
Come on now, they're your friends,
-他们只是关心你  -我知道
- they're just looking out after you. - I know.
我只是希望至少有那么一次
I just wish that once, I'd bring a guy home
能带一个他们真正喜欢的男人回家
that they actually liked.
那么你应该很清楚  如果不让他们见面
Well, you do realise that the odds of that happening are a little slimmer
-这种几率就愈发渺茫
- if they never get to meet the guy.
别再想了  罗斯
Let it go, Ross.
是啊  你又不认识芝芝
Yeah, well, you didn't know Chi Chi.
你们都保证了吗
Do you all promise?
对  我们保证
Yeah! We promise!
我们会很乖的
We'll be good!
钱德勒  你保证会很乖吗
Chandler? Do you promise to be good?
你可以进来
You can come in,
但你的过滤嘴小朋友得呆在外面
but your filter-tipped little buddy has to stay outside!
嘿  菲比
Hey, Pheebs.
亲爱的布菲小姐
'Dear Ms. Buffay.
谢谢你提醒我们的错误
Thank you for calling attention to our error.
我们已将五百元存入你的户头
We have credited your account with five hundred dollars.
造成不便之处请多包涵
We're sorry for the inconvenience,
此橄榄球电话是免费赠品
and hope you'll accept this football phone...
敬请笑纳
as our free gift.'
你们相信吗
Do you believe this?!
现在我多了一千块和一个橄榄球电话
Now I have a thousand dollars, and a football phone!
这是哪家银行
What bank is this?
注意  他来了
Hey. It's him.
-哪位  -我是艾伦
- Who is it? - It's Alan.
钱德勒  他来了
Chandler! He's here!
拜托要乖  千万要乖
Okay, please be good, please.
记得你们有多么爱我
Just remember how much you all like me.
嗨  艾伦  这是大家
Hi. Alan, this is everybody.
各位  这是艾伦
Everybody, this is Alan.
嗨  艾伦
Hi, Alan.
我对各位已经如雷贯耳了
I've heard schho much about all you guyschh!
谢谢  我明天再打电话给你
Thanks. I'll call you tomorrow.
好了  开始艾伦批斗大会吧
Okay. Okay, let's let the Alan-bashing begin.
谁先第一个发动啊
Who's gonna take the first shot, hmm?
来嘛
C'mon!
我先来
...I'll go.
我们先从他一直都很
Let's start with the way he kept picking at-
抱歉  我办不到  不行
You know, I'm sorry, I can't do this, can't do it.
我们很喜欢他
We loved him.
爱死他了  他太棒了
Loved him! Yeah! He's great!
等一下  我们谈的确定是
Wait a minute! We're talking about someone that
我现在约会的对象吗
I'm going out with?-
是啊
Yeah!
你们都有注意到
And did you notice...?
知道他什么最棒吗
Know what was great?
他笑起来有点歪
The way his smile was kinda crooked.
对  就像是鞋中人一样
Yes, yes! Like the man in the shoe!
鞋什么
...What shoe?
是童谣里的
From the nursery rhyme.
有一个歪歪男  笑起来歪歪的
'There was a crooked man, Who had a crooked smile,
他住在鞋子里  然后
Who lived in a shoe, For a... while...'
我认为艾伦
...So I think Alan
将成为衡量
will become the yardstick against which
未来所有男友的准绳
all future boyfriends will be measured.
什么未来男友
What future boyfriends?
不  我觉得  就是他了
No, no, I th- I think this could be, y'know, it.-
真的呀
Really!
仅凭他学戴维·哈塞霍夫的样子
Oh, yeah. I'd marry him just for his
连我自己都想嫁给他
David Hasselhof impression alone.
我以后在派对上也要表演这个
You know I'm gonna be doing that at parties, right?
知道我最喜欢他哪一点吗
You know what I like most about him, though?
哪一点
What?
他让我重拾了自信
The way he makes me feel about myself.
比赛结果如何
How was the game?
这个嘛
Well..
我们赢啦  谢谢  太棒啦
WE WON!! Thank you! Yes!
太好了  我有一个问题
That's fantastic! I have one question:
这怎么可能呢
How is that possible?
是艾伦  他真是太不可思议了
Alan.He was unbelievable.
他就像兔巴哥动画片中
He was like that-that-that Bugs Bunny cartoon
一人包揽所有位置的兔巴哥一样
where Bugs is playing all the positions, right,
只不过取而代之的是
but instead of Bugs it was
一垒手艾伦  二垒艾伦  三垒
first base-Alan, second base-Alan, third base-...
这就像是  他让我们团结一心
I mean, it-it was like, it was like he made us into a team.
对  我们让那些犹太教的珠宝商
Yep, we sure showed those Hassidic jewellers
领教了什么叫垒球
a thing or two about softball..
没错
Nice!
能问你们一个问题吗
Can I ask you guys a question?
你是否曾感觉艾伦可能  有时
D'you ever think that Alan is maybe.. sometimes..
怎样
What?
我说不上来  有点太艾伦了
...I dunno, a little too Alan?
不  不可能
Well, no. That's impossible.
他不可能太过于艾伦
You can never be too Alan.
没错  我们欣赏的就是那内在的艾伦感
Yeah, it's his, uh, innate Alan-ness that-that-that we adore.
我一个人就可以喝下一加仑的艾伦
I personally could have a gallon of Alan.
-嘿  莉琪  -嘿  怪女孩
- Hey, Lizzie. - Hey, Weird Girl.
我给你带了字母汤
I brought you alphabet soup.
元音字母都挑出去了吗
Did you pick out the vowels?
对  但我把"Y"留下来了
Yes. But I left in the Ys.
因为  Y是半元音嘛
'Cause, y'know, "sometimes y".
我还带了其他东西给你
Uh, I also have something else for you.
咸饼干吗
Saltines?
不  但你想要一千块钱和一个橄榄球电话吗
No, but would you like a thousand dollars and a football phone?
什么  天哪天哪  这里真的有钱
What? Oh, my God, Oh, my God, there's really money in here.
我知道
I know.
怪女孩  你在干嘛啊
Weird Girl, what are you doing?
别  我要送给你  我不想要
No, I want you to have it. I don't want it.
不  我得  送点东西给你
No, no, I ha-I have to give you something.
不  没关系  你不用
No, that's fine, you don't..
你要我的锡纸帽吗
Would you like my tin-foil hat?
不  你需要它
No. 'Cause you need that.
不用了  谢谢
No, it's okay, thanks.
求你了  让我表示一下吧
Please, let me do something.
好  这样吧
Okay, alright, I'll tell you what,
你请我喝汽水  我们就扯平了  好吗
you buy me a soda, and then we're even. Okay?
-好吧  -很好
- Okay. - Okay.
不用找了
Keep the change.
谢谢你  莉琪
Thanks, Lizzie.
你真的不要椒盐卷饼吗
Sure you don't wanna pretzel?
-不  不用了  谢谢  -回见
- No, I'm fine.Thanks. - See ya.
大拇指
A thumb?!
我知道  我知道
I know! I know,
我一打开  它就浮在里面
I opened it up and there it was, just floating in there,
像个迷你搭便车的人
like this tiny little hitch-hiker!
没准这是某种竞赛呢
Well, maybe it's a contest, y'know?
集满五个有奖
Like, collect all five?
-你们想看看吗  -不要
- Does, um, anyone wanna see? - Nooo!
-别这样  -快熄掉
- Oh, hey, don't do that! - Cut it out!
这比大拇指更糟糕
It's worse than the thumb!
嘿  这很不公平啊
Hey, this is so unfair!
怎么就不公平了
Oh, why is it unfair?
我有个缺点  又怎样
So I have a flaw! Big deal?
乔伊常扳指关节就不惹人厌吗
Like Joey's constant knuckle-cracking isn't annoying?
还有罗斯  把每个音发无比清楚
And Ross, with his over-pronouncing every single word?
莫妮卡大笑时的鼻音
And Monica, with that snort when she laughs?
这算搞什么嘛
I mean, what the hell is that thing?
我接受大家所有的缺点
I accept all those flaws,
为什么你们就不肯接受我呢
why can't you accept me for this?
扳指关节真的很惹人厌吗
...Does the knuckle-cracking bother everybody,
我觉得有一点点烦
Well, I-I could live without it.
是只是一点点惹人厌
Well, is it, like, a little annoying,
还是像菲比咬她的头发一样惹人厌
or is it like when Phoebe chews her hair?
别听他的  菲比
Oh, now, don't listen to him, Pheebs, all right?
我觉得那样很可爱
I think it's endearing.
哦  真的  是吗
Oh, "you do, do you"?
咬字清晰又不犯法
You know, there's nothing wrong with speaking correctly.
确实没错
"Indeed there isn't"...
我该回去工作了
I should really get back to work.
没错  不然客人们就会拿到
Yeah, 'cause otherwise someone might get
他们真正点的东西了
what they actually ordered.
刚吐出头发  就戴上拳击手套了哈
The hair comes out, and the gloves come on.
你有没有曾经和一个
Did you ever go out with a guy
你所有朋友都喜欢的男人约会
your friends all really like?
没有
No.
好吧  我在和一个我朋友都喜欢的男人约会
Okay.. Well, I'm going out with a guy my friends all really like.
等一下  你说的是那群丛原狼吗
Waitwait.. we talking about the coyotes here?
一头牛居然全身而退
All right, a cow got through!
你能相信吗
Can you believe it? ...
你知道吗  我没怎么动情
Y'know what? I just don't feel the thing.
他们倒是挺有感觉
I mean, they feel the thing,
而我却没有来电悸动
I don't feel the thing.
亲爱的  你应该永远保持鸡动
Honey.. you should always "feel" the thing.
听着  莫妮卡  如果你对他没感觉
Listen, if that's how you feel about the guy,
就把他甩了呀
Monica, dump him!
我知道  但真的很难
I know.. it's gonna be really hard.
他是大人了  他会熬过去的
Well, he's a big boy, he'll get over it.
不  他没事
No, he'll be fine.
我担心的是其他五人
It's the other five I'm worried about.
你对自己的身体就没一点尊重吗
Do you have any respect for your body?
你难道不清楚这对你身体的危害吗
Don't you realise what you're-you're doing to yourself?
喂  我受够你们了
Hey, y'know, I have had it with you guys
还有你们念叨的癌症  肺气肿和心脏病
and your cancer and your emphysema and your heart disease.
可无论怎样  抽烟很酷  你们懂的
The bottom line is, smoking is cool, and you know it.
钱德勒  艾伦的电话  他要找你
Chandler? It's Alan, he wants to speak to you.
真的吗  他找我
Really? He does?
老兄  什么事
Hey, buddy, what's up!
她告诉你了
Oh, she told you about that, huh.
对  我偶尔会犯烟瘾
Well, yeah, I have one now and then.
对  现在也是
Well, yeah, now.
没那么糟
Well, it's not that big- ..
这倒是真的
Well, that's true,..
天啊  以前从没人说过这样的话
Gee, y'know, no-one- no-one's ever put it like that before.
好的  谢谢
Well, okay, thanks!
天啊  他真神
God, he's good.
-如果他是个女人那该有多好  -是啊
- If only he were a woman. - Yeah.
"小羊排"
Ooh, Lambchop.
那袜子到底有多旧了
How old is that sock?
如果我手上戴着袜子三十年
If I had a sock on my hand for thirty years
它也会开口说话
it'd be talking too.
好吧  有人该换尼古丁贴片了
Okay. I think it's time to change somebody's nicotine patch.
嘿  乔伊在哪儿
Hey. Where's Joey?
乔伊吃了我的最后一片口香糖
Joey ate my last stick of gum,
我把他灭了
so I killed him.
你认为这样不对吗
Do you think that was wrong?
-他可能在对面  -谢谢
- I think he's across the hall. - Thanks.
好啦
There y'go.
哦  我又重拾快乐的生活了
Ooh, I'm alive with pleasure now.
菲比  你还想吃那个小烤饼吗  菲比
Hey Pheebs, you gonna have the rest of that Pop-Tart?.. Pheebs?
谁想吃剩下的小烤饼
Does anyone want the rest of this Pop-Tart?
我要吃
Hey, I might!
抱歉
I'm sorry. ..
那白痴汽水公司给了我
Y'know, those stupid soda people gave me
七千块当姆指的补偿金
seven thousand dollars for the thumb.
-天啊  -七千块
- Oh, my God. - 7 thousand dollars?
然后在来这的路上  我踩到了口香糖
And on my way over here, I stepped in gum.
这世界到底怎么了
...What is up with the universe?!
怎么啦
What's going on?
没什么  只是觉得正好大家都在
Nothing. I just think it's nice when we're all here together.
如果大家都有穿内裤会更好
Even nicer when everyone gets to wear their underwear..
-乔伊  你那里  -天呀
- Uh, Joey.. - Oh, God!
-好  -哦  是小羊排
- Okay.. - Oh! That was Lambchop!
好了  我们必须得谈谈
Please, guys, we have to talk.
等等  我有似曾相识的感觉
Wait, wait, I'm getting a deja vu...
不  不对
No, I'm not.
好吧  我们需要谈谈
Alright, we have to talk.
瞧来了
There it is!
是有关艾伦的事
Okay. It's-it's about Alan.
有件事应该让你们知道
There's something that you should know.
真的很难启齿
I mean, there's really no easy way to say this..
我决定和艾伦分手
I've decided to break up with Alan.
有第三者
Is there somebody else?
没有没有  只是因为
No, nononono.. it's just..
只是世事难料  人是会变的
y'know, things change. People change.
我们没变啊
We didn't change..
这就完了  没戏了吗
So that's it? It's over?
就这么结束了吗
Just like that?
当你放下一切防备
You know.. you let your guard down,
开始真心对待一个人时  我真的
you start to really care about someone, and I just- I-
-我可以继续伪装  -好啊
- Look, I- I could go on pretending. - Okay!
不  这样对我不公平
No, but that wouldn't be fair to me,
对艾伦不公平
it wouldn't be fair to Alan.
对你们大家也不公平
It wouldn't be fair to you!
是吗  谁要公平
Yeah, who wants fair?
我只想事情回到之前的样子
I mean, I just want things back. Y'know, the way they were.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry..
她还抱歉  我感觉好多了
Oh, she's sorry! I feel better!
我真是不敢相信
I just can't believe this!
假期就要来临了
I mean, with the holidays coming up-
我还想带他去见我的家人
I wanted him to meet my family-
我会找到新男友的  会有另一个艾伦
I'll meet somone else. There'll be other Alans.
是啊  好吧
Oh, yeah! Right!
你们不会有事吧
Are you guys gonna be okay?
我们会好起来的
Hey hey, we'll be fine.
我们只是需要一点时间
We're just gonna need a little time.
我了解
I understand.
我真的很抱歉
I'm, I'm really sorry.
我也很抱歉
Yeah, I mean, I'm sorry too.
但说实话  我也觉得稍稍解脱了
But, I gotta tell you, I am a little relieved.
解脱
Relieved?
对  我和你在一起很开心
Yeah, well, I had a great time with you..
只是我受不了你朋友
I just can't stand your friends.
记得我们到中央公园划船吗
Remember when we went to Central Park and rented boats?..
那真好玩
That was fun.
是啊  他划得就像维京人一样
Yeah. He could row like a viking.
情况如何
So how'd it go?
嗯  你知道
Oh, y'know..
他有提到我们吗
Did did he mention us?
他说他会想念你们的
He said he's really gonna miss you guys.
这一天很不好过吧
You had a rough day, huh?-
那还用说
Oh, you have no idea...
来
C'mere.
-我受够了  我要抽烟  -不行
- That's it. I'm getting cigarettes. - No no no!
我管不了那么多了
I don't care, I don't care!
我投降  我是懦夫  我要抽烟
Game's over! I'm weak! I've gotta smoke!
我一定要抽烟
I've gotta have the smoke!
如果你不再抽烟  我就给你七千块
If you never smoke again I'll give you seven thousand dollars!
好吧  没问题
Yeah, alright.